Wil Buchanan

williamjamesbuchanan@gmail.com | 863-259-0202 | linkedin.com/in/williamjamesbuchanan | wijabu.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

An aspiring full-stack web developer with six years of technical solutions experience in the hospitality industry. A curious and creative problem solver pivoting careers and bringing diverse experience from both military and civilian positions with superb interpersonal communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

LMS, Inc. Mar 2017 – Feb 2023

Six-year contractor with Princess Cruises. Created department to test and fix guest data for the billion-dollar OceanMedallion program

Director, Data Integrity Experience Operations – July 2021 – Feb 2023

- Directed six Data Analysts; investigated and resolved inconsistencies between SQL and NoSQL databases
- Led Data Integrity Pod through Agile development of PII security and consistency throughout ecosystem
- Scripted JavaScript toolset to automate fixes to common issues; reduced incident resolution time by 75%

Project Manager & Application Support Lead – Sep 2019 – July 2021

- Designed holistic Jira roadmap tracking hundreds of user stories and epics; provided real-time status to VPs
- Piloted weekly cross-functional meeting; analyzed issue trends with developers; defined priority of solutions
- Compiled APIs to simulate Guest Experience; tested via JavaScript; uncovered gaps among microservices

Senior Technical Integration Specialist & Business Analyst – Mar 2017 – Sep 2019

- Tested the Guest Experience in a live production environment; recorded new friction points and use cases
- Published dozens of text and video training materials; trained fellows on resolution of common problems
- Tracked, managed, and solved incidents via ServiceNow; integrated with PagerDuty to automate alerting

Public Affairs Superintendent – Florida Air National Guard

Sep 2018 – May 2023

Retired. Spent 13 years in Public Affairs reporting on military deployments, hurricane recovery and COVID-19 vaccine distribution

- Trained journalists in AP style, content creation and media relations; oversaw reporting on 200+ ANG events
- Built cloud-based dynamic schedule to centralize mission organization; reduced man hours by 60%
- Managed 48 Airmen across 14 counties to distribute 87,083 COVID-19 vax for Operation Warp Speed

EDUCATION

Web Development Bootcamp – Full-stack web applications – Udemy	2023
Master of Arts – Cognitive Science & Interpersonal Communication – University of Central Florida	2013
Bachelor of Arts – Journalism – University of Central Florida	2009

LANGUAGES, SKILLS AND TOOLS

 JavaScript 	Express	 ServiceNow
 HTML 	• SQL	 Jira / Confluence
CSS	MongoDB	■ Agile
NodeJS	■ Git / GitHub	